The Practice Fusion iPad app
liberates doctors from their desktops
and let them spend more time on what
matters most, which is treating patients.
The app works seamlessly with Practice
Fusion's robust free web-based system
so that all patient information
that they've already invested in
is available at the doctor's fingertips.
The app lets doctors both review
and write medical charts.
It makes it easy and fast for the
doctor to learn about their upcoming
patient visits and to examine each chart
in as much detail as they need.
This is how you use the
app during an appointment.
All patients that are coming
in today are shown in the schedule.
You can also see a quick summary about
each patient and why they're coming in.
There's also a picture and quick demographic
information that lets you understand
who the patient is, everything that the
doctor needs to prepare for the appointment.
It's easy to learn more about a patient.
The patient summary shows
all the salient information
that the doctor needs on a single sheet.
There's previous illnesses,
medications, and allergies –
everything that the doctor needs to
understand the person's state of health.
When the patient tells the doctor
about their health problems,
the app makes it easy to note down
the information right into the system.
One way doctors can enter
information is using dictation.
With dictation, they can record and
transcribe exactly what the patient says,
which allows the doctor to capture
a lot of information really quickly.
They can also use Practice
Fusion's templates
that they're using on the
web-based system, on the iPad.
These contain lots of common observations
that the doctor can put
straight into the chart.
And just in case, there's an
option for manually typing,
though we think that they
really won't need it that often.
The information is entered into the patient's
chart on the left side of the screen.
When the doctor makes a diagnosis, he can
enter it from a list of common diseases
or type a few letters to find
the exact word he's looking for.
The app also leverages order sets.
These groups of doctors' orders and
prescriptions make it easy for the doctor
to enter in a whole set of items
that are pertinent for this patient.
With the iPad app, doctors can
modify the order sets on the fly
and with a few taps, customize the
treatment for this particular patient.
And the patient chart is done.
The doctor didn't even have
to type a single word.
This saves a lot of time and effort.
The doctor doesn't have to spend
time writing in the chart after work,
transcribing from paper,
or trying to remember details
from a visit earlier in the day.
Practice Fusion's iPad app
helps doctors be more efficient
and increases the amount of time
and focus they have with their patients.
This is modern medicine in action.